PROFILE



PROFESSION

COMMUNICATIONS, GOVERNANCE AND PUBLIC POLICY CONSULTANT

ADDRESS:

Valley View Drive-Utawala 11624- 00100 +254724267087/+254733694513 adiemaadiema@gmail.com

Twitter: @TheDebateGuru

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/kingjosiahadiemaadiema/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Josiah is a considered Debate Guru; with an over 8-year extensive experience as a Public Speaking and Debate Trainer, Event MC and Moderator, Media Specialist, A freelance Journalist, Trainer of Trainers, Facilitator, Social Media Trainer and Influencer.

He has conducted Training and Consultancy for various organizations on Communication: Effective Communication, Social Media, Debate and Public Speaking and extensive engagement in Governance and Public Policy especially on Youth and Governance, Young Women Participation in Governance, Gender Responsive Public Service and Public Policy.

Besides, he is a Mentor with several Organizations where he nurtures and inspires Youths on many fronts of engagement with a forte on raising voices of the marginalised within the society.

Currently, he is the Managing Director of Lean Leap Consultants; a fast-growing firm with solutions to organisational needs where we offer up to date and innovative solutions to pivotal areas of your organisation and conduct trainings that build and sustain the capacity to enhance entities achieve their set

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

The University of Nairobi

Sept 2019 - 2021

Masters on Research and Public Policy

Uganda Christian University

Oct. 2010

B.A Mass Communication

EXPERIENCE

Managing Director: Lean Leap Consultants

In charge of the team and expansion of Lean Leap Consultants with a critical focus to detail our services to our client needs especially Engagement and Trainings in;

- Communication,
- Public Policy and Governance
- Social Media
- Debate and Public Speaking.

Consultancies

UN Women Eastern and Southern Region (ESAR)

 Training ESAR Staff and Partners on Editorial and Report Writing and Thematic Public Policy Reporting

Partnership for African Social and Governance Research (PASGR)

- Social Media Outreach and Influencing
- Social Media Online Monitoring and Evaluation
- Report compilation and Writing

Konrad Adenauer Stiftung

- Report Writing in KAS Online Engagements in 2020
- Moderator for KAS during the Online Panel Discussions

Rapporteur Inter Regional Economic Network (IREN)

Report Writing during the Enactus Online Engagement Forum 2022

Youth Coordinator - Action Aid Kenya Mar 2018 - Dec 2018

- Manage Youth Programming Finances within the ActionAid Network
- Moderating and mobilization for youth activities
- Developing and implementing a strategy on youth organizing and activism
- Develop and conduct youth training, facilitate small scale youth activities, meetings and workshops.
- Program implementation & reporting
- Develop and implement budgets for youth activities.

Executive Director – Community Podium Initiative Dec 2016- Mar 2018

- Head of CPI
- Institute, Develop and implement CPI's Development Strategic Plan

Develop and initiate viable Partnerships for CPI

Executive Director -Kenya National Debate Council (KNDC) Jun 2014- Nov 2016

- Head of KNDC
- Implement KNDC's development and expansion agenda.
- Formulate worthwhile partnerships that will benefit KNDC and execute the KNDC year Planner and strategic plan

Communications Director - SavyyPol Consulting Group Ltd

- Establish a Communication Department in Savvypol
- Run daily Communication of SavvyPol Group.

Moderator Student Guild Presidential Debates – St. Pauls University Limuru-March 2013

Moderated the student Guild Presidential Debates at the St. Pauls University-Main Campus, Limuru for the Student Council elections 2013.

Debate Moderator Nakuru Youth Summit

Moderated debates at the Nakuru Youth Summit which was hosted by the World Development Global Alliance (WDGA) and Yes Youth Can- Rift Valley for the peace initiative in Rift Valley.

SKILLS & ABILITIES

- Research and Analytical Skills
- Report Writing
- Public Policy Analyst
- Event Mceeing and Moderation
- Trainer Public Speaking, Debate and Critical Thinking.
- Social Media trainer, strategist and consultant

LEADERSHIP

- Youth Trainer and Mentor with Emerging Leaders Foundation
- Associate Trainer at Action Aid Global Platform
- Spice Chungu Mentor and Partner
- Mentor Emerging Leaders Foundation

CERTIFICATIONS

- Honours College Leadership Programme (UCU) Aug 2011-May 2009
- Political Facilitation Training- MSTCDC Oct 2018
- Trainer of trainer Advance Certificate Action Aid Dec 2017

REFEREES

Dr. Gedion Onyango (PhD).

Lecturer; Department of Political Science and Public Administration University of Nairobi Mahatma Gandhi Wing, 4th Floor +254-771717582

Email: onyangoj@uonbi.ac.ke

Teresia Mwangi Anderson

Manager, Global Platform Kenya (AAIK) Nairobi-Kenya +254 722 589 566

Email: tmw@ms.dk

Kipngeno Kirui Duncan

Managing Director Savvypol Consulting Group P.O Box 8729 - 00200, Nairobi, Kenya +254 725 570 132

Email: kipngeno.kirui@gmail.com